Jane G. Austin papers, ca. 1870-1894
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Jane G. Austin papers, ca. 1870-1894
MS 115
Austin, Jane G. (Jane Goodwin)
The bulk of the collection contains undated, holographic manuscripts with edits, of three of Austin's novels and eleven of her short stories.
.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
American Author
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Letters, 1889-1891
Series II: Works, ca. 1870-1891
Series III: Miscellaneous, 1890-1894
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection contains undated, holographic manuscripts with edits, of three of Austin's novels and eleven of her short stories. The novels constitute three of a four-part series published as the "Pilgrim Books:" 1889, Standish of Standish; 1890, Betty Alden; and 1891, Doctor Le Baron and His Daughters. Also, five letters to Austin containing information on historical personages, and appreciation of her writing. Miscellaneous items include poems, drawings, a studio portrait of her taken in 1890, and genealogical background material for her own family, of Plymouth, Mass., as well as the 17th and 18th century New England families presented in her works.
Access Terms
Goodwin family -- Genealogy
Historical fiction, American
Women authors, American
New England -- Social life and customs -- To 1775
Correspondence
Photographs
Manuscripts
Illustrations
Photoprints
Container List
- Series I: Letters, 1889-1891
  - Letters. 1889-1891 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Works, ca. 1870-1891
  - "Between the Belfrey and the Ground; a Story of Boston in 1775." 10 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Children of the Mayflower; the Third Story." 17 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "The Mandarin at Midnight." (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Scipio's Supper; a Legend of Old Plymouth." 8 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "A Terrible Thanksgiving Day." 24 leaves. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Betty Alden; the First-born Daughter of the Pilgrims. 725 leaves. Published by Houghton, Mifflin & Co., the Riverside Press, Cambridge. 1891 (Box 1, Folder 7-11)
  - Doctor LeBarron and His Daughters. 832 leaves. Published by Houghton, Mifflin & Co., the Riverside Press, Cambridge. 1890 (Box 1, Folder 12-18)
  - "Behind the Convent Grille." 81 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "The Gold Wells." 55 leaves and 1 leaf (numbered "25") of another version. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Golden Chains." 21 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "The Little Man in Grey." 17 leaves. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - [untitled] First sentence: "Goodmorningg, is it to be a rainy day?" 23 pages. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "A Daughter of the Puritans." 50 leaves. Also 1 leaf outline entitled: "The Next Page." (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Standish of Standish. 602 leaves. Published by Houghton, Mifflin & Co., the Riverside Press, Cambridge. 1889 (Box 2, Folder 7-10)
- Series III: Miscellaneous, 1890-1894
  - Genealogical Notes (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Material (photograph, poetry, sketches, etc.) (Box 2, Folder 12)